







Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Tech Architect

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Engineering Management, Technical Architect, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C++, Win SDK, Visual

C++,VC++,JAVA,J2EE,Shell Scripting, Microservices, Go,AWS

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Summary

19+ years of experience in Information Technology in Application/Product engineering, management in areas including Storage Networking and cloud, Banking/Financial Services and Licensing/Security/Cryptography.

10 + years of experience in managing, leading globally distributed engineering teams on large / enterprise projects.

16+ years of varied hands-on experience in C, C++, and JAVA/J2EE technologies.

10+ years of experience into product development in Storage Networking, Licensing/Security/Cryptography. 5+ years of sound experience in Application development and Enterprise Application Integration in Banking/Financial Services

Sound experience with architecture/design and developing enterprise Products/Applications and SDK/API Design (frameworks / SDKs / web services) and multi-threading.

Sound knowledge of varied Operating Systems like Windows, *NIX/UNIX flavors, and cross platform development with c/C++ and sound knowledge of low level/system programming and OS Internals

Work Experience

Infinite Computer Solutions (India) Limited as Technical Lead/Architect May 2020 to Till Date

Responsibilities:

Technical proposal/design preparation. Engineering management and Onboard Onsite/Offshore team Requirements gathering and solution designing. Participate in development and reviews.

Synopsis: Enhance and develop new features on IBM cloud VPC, like Create point in time snapshot for mission-critical data to S3 compatible storage and restore the data using lazy and fast restore. Provide ability to list, view, and delete any snapshot on demand. Provide user ability from UI, API and CLI utilities to copy snapshots across COS regions, Snapshot lifecycle management with create restore snapshots in an encrypted and secured way. Core Technologies: Golang, Golang frameworks, Web Services, REST, Mcro Services, IBM cloud, containers and Kubernetes and extensions, Linux, Mac, storage technologies.

DELL EMC as Engineering Lead/Manager Oct 2009 to Oct 2019

Core Technologies: C, C++, Win SDK, core Java, Windows, Linux, UNIX, AWS/Azure, OpenSSL, Cryptography/ Security, Other Keywords: JAVAJ2EE, Golang, Shell Scripting, XML, STL, Web Services, REST, Micro Services, DevOps, Automation.

Responsibilities:

Lead engineering team and architect/design licensing solutions as per specifications to ensured standards and policies are adhered to, by utilizing best of the industry standard tools and methodologies. Responsible for end to end delivery of multiple releases of CLP product over the last 10 years, including

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

organization/people responsibilities including vendors and distributed teams.

Responsible for delivering product software and product management with best industry standards and methodologies like Agile, Scrum, Pair programming, Pivotal, Cl, CD, TDD, BDD.

Work with all DELLEMC product development and management teams, at various phases of product life cycle, to assist them with onboarding to CLP platform including requirements planning, product strategies, development and post implementation issues.

SME in Common Licensing Platform for EMC products. Design/Development and provide appropriate licensing solutions in C/C++/Java for Electronic License Management Systems and Common Licensing Platform for EMC products' and enablement on various operating systems and platforms like Windows, Linux/Unix and other platforms Accountable for design and development of various platform independent C (Win SDK), C++ and JAVA API for EMC products and support over 32 + operating system flavors.

Designed and implemented static/dynamic link libraries based on security standards, best practices and design patterns, designed / developed applications, and implemented a number of APIs / web services / calls.

Secure programming practices and strict security standards (e.g. RSA) were followed.

Performed build, deployed, configured Security services that did Management of Encrypted Keys, Certificates. Implemented CI/CD with various tools to improve release cycles through build and test automaton.

Synopsis: Electronic License Management System is combination of various software systems and services which enable all EMC products for electronic licensing and designed to improve business processes and system capabilities that support revenue generation and the Total Customer Experience (TCE). Common Licensing Platform (CLP) is an application programming interface (API) that controls licensing of software product features through common processes and functions. The CLP API can be used by programs written in Java, C++, and C. CLP is one of the deliverables from EMC's ELMS (Electronic License Management System) initiative. ELMS has implemented various initiatives like transformational licensing solution with usage intelligence and predictive data analytics.

Wipro Technologies Pvt Ltd as Module Lead/Team Lead Oct 2003 to Mar 2009

Worked extensively on Storage Area Networks (SAN) for more than 3 years. Involved in Storage Virtualization Product Development and Testing. Hands on experience in storage technologies like RAID, FC, SCSI, Tape Library, and CIM, SM-S

Worked extensively on BFSI Domain for more than 4 years. Involved in Application Development for major/reputed clients. Gained experience in BFS domain knowledge in middle office and trading systems.

Lead the offshore development team, Design and development of new features, develop software modules and bug fixing.

Day to day basis, involved working with clients for requirements gathering, coordination with onsite/offshore stakeholders. Managed the entire development life cycle including need assessment, designing and development, and team management.

Received client's accolades on many occasions.

Core Technologies: C, C++, JAVA/J2EE, Linux, *NIX/UNIX, TIB/Rendezvous, CORBA, Orbix, SAN, JUnit, JNI, Shell Scripting

^ Back to Top

Education

 $\hbox{UG: B.Sc (Hectronics) from Andhra Loyola College, Vijawada, Andhra Pradesh. in 1994 and Vijawada, Andhra$

PG: MCA (Computers) from Blooms College of Computers, Osmania University, Andhra Pradesh. in 1999

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: GMTE (General Management program for IT executives) Certified Scrum Master CSM TOGAF

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C, C++, Core Java/J2EE,GDB, Make file		2019	16 Year(s)
PL/SQL, XML, SNMP, Shell Scripting		2019	10 Year(s)
VC++, Eclipse, TIB/Rendezvous		2019	10 Year(s)
COWDCOM, CORBA, TIBCO.		2013	8 Year(s)
Unix, Linux, Windows, Unix Internals		2019	14 Year(s)
Clear Case, JUnit, MS Visual Sourcesafe		2019	15 Year(s)
OOAD, Purify, Rational Purify,PCF		2019	15 Year(s)
Rational Rose, UML, Design Patterns		2019	16 Year(s)
Spring, spring cloud, web services/REST		2019	5 Year(s)
CI/CD with Jenkins, Scripting		2019	10 Year(s)
STL, PThread, Boost, OpenSSL, FlexNet, X		2019	10 Year(s)
Al and ML with python and R, Hadoop and		2019	6 Year(s)
AWS, Microsoft Azure, & PCF		2019	5 Year(s)
C, C++, Core Java/J2EE, Python		2019	16 Year(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

anguaga Drafiaianay Dood Weita Chash

English Proficient vviite Speak

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: Athena Client: Lehman Brothers Nature of Employment: Full Time Role: Module Leader

Duration: Oct 2007 - Mar 2009 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: C/C++, VC++, Linux, Solaris, Windows, Sybase, TIB/Rendezvous

Project Details: Athena is the middle office system of Lehman Brothers. It is a Booking system serving range of functionality like capturing executions from METS and basket trading systems, allocating them to the respective accounts, calculating commissions and taxes and generating ITS records. Stocks and convertible bonds can be booked through Athena

Project Title: SMDB Reengineering Client: Bank of New York Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: May 2006 - Oct 2007 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Module Leader Skill Used: C/C++, Linux, Solaris, CORBA, Orbix

Project Details: The Security Master Database (SMDB) provides a comprehensive repository of information regarding all existing security instruments, sub-instruments and legal entities. The tools provided allow you to review and edit information regarding these items, as well as add new instruments and issuers to the database. The project focuses its effort on rebuilding the SMDB system based on a configurable set of database driven mappings, defaulting and validations. The project documents and replaces all mappings, defaulting and validations within phase A2. As such the projects investment in a better documented and more flexible application.

Project Title: VSMOpen (Indigo)

Client: StorageTek

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2003 - May 2006 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: C, Linux, Java, SAN, JUnit, JNI, Rational ClearQuest, Shell scripts

Project Details: Indigo is the code name for a virtual tape and virtual library product. This product provides virtual tape drives and tape libraries, which in turn provide functionality similar to real tape drives and libraries, while eliminating physical constraints and sources of errors. This product will be compatible with both open systems (UNIX and Windows) and M/S systems. The product will be highly scalable, with capacities ranging from small systems capable of providing a few hundred M/S/s of throughput to very large systems capable of multiple GB/s of throughput. The number of virtual devices (virtual tape drives and virtual libraries) available will range from 512 for small systems to 8,192 for the largest systems. Data written to the Indigo system will be stored on tape or disk resources managed by the Indigo system. A webbased GUI and a CLI interface are provided for administrative functions. Extensive reporting of the actions and status of the system is provided by the same interface.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.